A Guide to the The Edgar Cayce Readings, 1886-2020
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Readings, 1886-2020
The Edgar Cayce Foundation, Virginia Beach, Virginia
Coll.9
127 Linear Feet
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in boxes according to Gladys Davis Turner's original numbering system. Each number represents a reading recipient, and the readings for each number are arranged in chronological order. For example, the first reading for 262 is denoted by 262-1. Accompanying material is also arranged chronologically by day, month and year.
The collection is further arranged into 5 series:
1. Readings and correspondence:
Transcriptions of the readings and background information, reports, and correspondence.
2. Gladys Davis work files:
Primary source materials relating to Edgar Cayce's work collected by secretary and stenographer Gladys Davis Turner.
3. Original readings and correspondence:
Readings and correspondence sent at time of reading then later donated to the E.C.F. by reading recipients and/or their families.
4. Reports addition:
Reports from reading recipients found in Gladys Davis Turner's files.
5. Source file:
Secondary sources on particular readings created by Gladys Davis, Charles Sinex and the E.C.F. staff in the mid-1970s.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of original copies of Edgar Cayce's readings, accompanying case files, correspondence, and supplementary research.
As Edgar Cayce gave a reading in trance, his wife Gertrude would serve as the conductor. She guided the reading and offered the questions posed by the reading recipient. Cayce's stenographer Gladys Davis Turner would record the reading in shorthand, then transcribe her notes into two typewritten copies. One would be given to the reading recipient, while the other was retained in a case file.
Turner maintained the readings and accompanying material from 1923 until her death in 1986. She arranged the records and consistently updated the case files with new information she collected about reading recipients. Her diligence created an extensive record of how readings may or may not have affected recipient's lives, and a collection of data to study the veracity of the readings over time.
From 1959 to 1971, Turner led the Readings Indexing Project to create a Master Index for study. The readings were also microfilmed, and later converted to CD-ROM and online formats.
Reading recipients were given numbers to maintain their anonymity and Turner took the responsibility seriously to maintain confidentiality while making the information accessible. She wrote in the November 1940 A.R.E. Bulletin that "It is important for members of the Association to realize how impersonally this work is done. All readings bear a file number. The cards and extracted material bear only the file number and can in no way be related to any particular individual."
These records form the foundation of the Association for Research and Enlightenment's activities and make Edgar Cayce one of the most documented psychics of the twentieth century.
- Readings and correspondence
  - Box 1, 1-18, case files 1-18
  - Box 2, 19-35, casefiles 19-35
  - Box 3, 36-60, casefiles 36-60
  - Box 4, 61-87, casefiles 61-87
  - Box 5, 88-106, casefiles 88-106
  - Box 6, 106-132, casefiles 106-132
  - Box 7, 133 - 137-20, casefiles 133 - 137-20
  - Box 8, 137-21 - 137, casefiles 137-21 - 137
  - Box 9, 138-149, casefiles 138-149
  - Box 10, 150-165, casefiles 150-165
  - Box 11, 165-191, casefiles 165-191
  - Box 12, 192-195, casefiles 192-195
  - Box 13, 195-203, casefiles 195-203
  - Box 14, 204-227, casefiles 204-227
  - Box 15, 228-243, casefiles 228-243
  - Box 16, 243 - 254-39, casefiles 243 - 254-39
  - Box 17, 254-40 - 255, casefiles 254-40 - 255
  - Box 18, 255 - 257-39, casefiles 255 - 257-39
  - Box 19, 257-40 - 257-150, casefiles 257-40 - 257-150
  - Box 20, 257-226 - 257, casefiles 257-226 - 257
  - Box 21, 257, casefile 257
  - Box 22, 257 - 261-35, casefiles 257 - 261-35
  - Box 23, 261 - 262-80, casefiles 261 - 262-80
  - Box 24, 262-81 - 264-60, casefiles 262-81 - 264-60
  - Box 25, 264, casefile 264
  - Box 26, 265-270, casefiles 265-270
  - Box 27, 270 - 275-25, casefiles 270 - 275-25
  - Box 28, 275-26 - 279-20, casefiles 275-26 - 279-20
  - Box 29, 279-283, casefiles 279-283
  - Box 30, 284-288, casefiles 284-288
  - Box 31, 288, casefiles 288
  - Box 32, 288, casefiles 288
  - Box 33, 288, casefiles 288
  - Box 34, 289-294, casefiles 289-294
  - Box 35, 294, casefiles 294
  - Box 36, 294, casefiles 294
  - Box 37, 294, casefiles 294
  - Box 38, 294, casefiles 294
  - Box 39, 294, casefiles 294
  - Box 40, 294, casefiles 294
  - Box 41, 294-295, casefiles 294-295
  - Box 42, 295-303, casefiles 295-303
  - Box 43, 303-304, casefiles 303-304
  - Box 44, 305-307, casefiles 305-307
  - Box 45, 307-312, casefiles 307-312
  - Box 46, 313-320, casefiles 313-320
  - Box 47, 321-325, casefiles 321-325
  - Box 48, 326-333, casefiles 326-333
  - Box 49, 333-337, casefiles 333-337
  - Box 50, 338-341, casefiles 338-341
  - Box 51, 341, casefiles 341
  - Box 52, 341-342, casefiles 341-342
  - Box 53, 343-349, casefiles 343-349
  - Box 54, 349-353, casefiles 349-353
  - Box 55, 354-365, casefiles 354-365
  - Box 56, 366-370, casefiles 366-370
  - Box 57, 370-374, casefiles 370-374
  - Box 58, 375-388, casefiles 375-388
  - Box 59, 389-391, casefiles 389-391
  - Box 60, 391-403, casefiles 391-403
  - Box 61, 404-410, casefiles 404-410
  - Box 62, 411-416, casefiles 411-416
  - Box 63, 417-423, casefiles 417-423
  - Box 64, 424-435, casefiles 424-435
  - Box 65, 436-1 - 438, casefiles 436-1 - 438
  - Box 66, 438-439, casefiles 438-439
  - Box 67, 440-1 - 451, casefiles 440-1 - 451
  - Box 68, 452 - 462-18, casefiles 452 - 462-18
  - Box 69, 462-464, casefiles 462-464
  - Box 70, 464 - 480-56, casefiles 464 - 480-56
  - Box 71, 480-487, casefiles 480-487
  - Box 72, 487-498, casefiles 487-498
  - Box 73, 499-515, casefiles 499-515
  - Box 74, 516-528, casefiles 516-528
  - Box 75, 529 - 538-44, casefiles 529 - 538-44
  - Box 76, 538-25 - 541, casefiles 538-25 - 541
  - Box 77, 542-550, casefiles 542-550
  - Box 78, 551-1 - 560, casefiles 551-1 - 560
  - Box 79, 561-573, casefiles 561-573
  - Box 80, 573-585, casefiles 573-585
  - Box 81, 585-586, casefiles 585-586
  - Box 82, 587-601, casefiles 587-601
  - Box 83, 601-617, casefiles 601-617
  - Box 84, 618-631, casefiles 618-631
  - Box 85, 631-640, casefiles 631-640
  - Box 86, 641-648, casefiles 641-648
  - Box 87, 649-671, casefiles 649-671
  - Box 88, 672-693, casefiles 672-693
  - Box 89, 694-717, casefiles 694-717
  - Box 90, 718-757, casefiles 718-757
  - Box 91, 758-772, casefiles 758-772
  - Box 92, 773-779, casefiles 773-779
  - Box 93, 779, casefiles 779
  - Box 94, 780-808, casefiles 780-808
  - Box 95, 808-811, casefiles 808-811
  - Box 96, 812-826, casefiles 812-826
  - Box 97, 826-848, casefiles 826-848
  - Box 98, 849, casefiles 849
  - Box 99, 849-862, casefiles 849-862
  - Box 100, 863-887, casefiles 863-887
  - Box 101, 888 - 900-80, casefiles 888 - 900-80
  - Box 102, 900-81 - 900-199, casefiles 900-81 - 900-199
  - Box 103, 900-200 - 900-324, casefiles 900-200 - 900-324
  - Box 104, 900-325 - 900-468, casefiles 900-325 - 900-468
  - Box 105, 900, casefiles 900
  - Box 106, 900, casefiles 900
  - Box 107, 900, casefiles 900
  - Box 108, 900-903, casefiles 900-903
  - Box 109, 904-933, casefiles 904-933
  - Box 110, 934, casefiles 934
  - Box 111, 935-952, casefiles 935-952
  - Box 112, 953-956, casefiles 953-956
  - Box 113, 957-979, casefiles 957-979
  - Box 114, 980-996, casefiles 980-996
  - Box 115, 997-1009, casefiles 997-1009
  - Box 116, 1010-1039, casefiles 1010-1039
  - Box 117, 1040-1079, casefiles 1040-1079
  - Box 118, 1080-1100, casefiles 1080-1100
  - Box 119, 1100, casefiles 1100
  - Box 120, 1100-1122, casefiles 1100-1122
  - Box 121, 1122-1143, casefiles 1122-1143
  - Box 122, 1144-1158, casefiles 1144-1158
  - Box 123, 1158-1173, casefiles 1158-1173
  - Box 124, 1174-1187, casefiles 1174-1187
  - Box 125, 1188-1207, casefiles 1188-1207
  - Box 126, 1208, casefiles 1208
  - Box 127, 1208, casefiles 1208
  - Box 128, 1209-1241, casefiles 1209-1241
  - Box 129, 1242-1292, casefiles 1242-1292
  - Box 130, 1293-1325, casefiles 1293-1325
  - Box 131, 1326-1360, casefiles 1326-1360
  - Box 132, 1361-1392, casefiles 1361-1392
  - Box 133, 1393-1424, casefiles 1393-1424
  - Box 134, 1425-1445, casefiles 1425-1445
  - Box 135, 1446-1467, casefiles 1446-1467
  - Box 136, 1467-1472, casefiles 1467-1472
  - Box 137, 1472-1486, casefiles 1472-1486
  - Box 138, 1487-1512, casefiles 1487-1512
  - Box 139, 1513-1538, casefiles 1513-1538
  - Box 140, 1539-1561, casefiles 1539-1561
  - Box 141, 1561-1578, casefiles 1561-1578
  - Box 142, 1579-1602, casefiles 1579-1602
  - Box 143, 1603-1631, casefiles 1603-1631
  - Box 144, 1632-1641, casefiles 1632-1641
  - Box 145, 1642-1663, casefiles 1642-1663
  - Box 146, 1663-1688, casefiles 1663-1688
  - Box 147, 1689-1713, casefiles 1689-1713
  - Box 148, 1714-1743, casefiles 1714-1743
  - Box 149, 1744-1770, casefiles 1744-1770
  - Box 150, 1770-1779, casefiles 1770-1779
  - Box 151, 1780-1800, casefiles 1780-1800
  - Box 152, 1800-1819, casefiles 1800-1819
  - Box 153, 1820-1851, casefiles 1820-1851
  - Box 154, 1852-1861, casefiles 1852-1861
  - Box 155, 1861-1868, casefiles 1861-1868
  - Box 156, 1868-1889, casefiles 1868-1889
  - Box 157, 1890-1923, casefiles 1890-1923
  - Box 158, 1924-1946, casefiles 1924-1946
  - Box 159, 1947-1976, casefiles 1947-1976
  - Box 160, 1977-2001, casefiles 1977-2001
  - Box 161, 2002-2015, casefiles 2002-2015
  - Box 162, 2016-2052, casefiles 2016-2052
  - Box 163, 2053-2066, casefiles 2053-2066
  - Box 164, 2067, casefiles 2067
  - Box 165, 2067-2071, casefiles 2067-2071
  - Box 166, 2072-2087, casefiles 2072-2087
  - Box 167, 2087-2110, casefiles 2087-2110
  - Box 168, 2111-2129, casefiles 2111-2129
  - Box 169, 2130-2156, casefiles 2130-2156
  - Box 170, 2157-2179, casefiles 2157-2179
  - Box 171, 2180-2229, casefiles 2180-2229
  - Box 172, 2230-2279, casefiles 2230-2279
  - Box 173, 2280-2318, casefiles 2280-2318
  - Box 174, 2319-2341, casefiles 2319-2341
  - Box 175, 2354-2393, casefiles 2354-2393
  - Box 176, 2394-2425, casefiles 2394-2425
  - Box 177, 2426-2454, casefiles 2426-2454
  - Box 178, 2455-2459, casefiles 2455-2459
  - Box 179, 2460-2487, casefiles 2460-2487
  - Box 180, 2487-2513, casefiles 2487-2513
  - Box 181, 2514-2532, casefiles 2514-2532
  - Box 182, 2533-2555, casefiles 2533-2555
  - Box 183, 2556-2593, casefiles 2556-2593
  - Box 184, 2594-2633, casefiles 2594-2633
  - Box 185, 2634-2671, casefiles 2634-2671
  - Box 186, 2672-2704, casefiles 2672-2704
  - Box 187, 2705-2739, casefiles 2705-2739
  - Box 188, 2740-2776, casefiles 2740-2776
  - Box 189, 2777-2799, casefiles 2777-2799
  - Box 190, 2800-2824, casefiles 2800-2824
  - Box 191, 2824-2843, casefiles 2824-2843
  - Box 192, 2844-2880, casefiles 2844-2880
  - Box 193, 2881-2902, casefiles 2881-2902
  - Box 194, 2903-2935, casefiles 2903-2935
  - Box 195, 2936-2949, casefiles 2936-2949
  - Box 196, 2950-2970, casefiles 2950-2970
  - Box 197, 2971-2982, casefiles 2971-2982
  - Box 198, 2982, casefiles 2982
  - Box 199, 2983-2998, casefiles 2983-2998
  - Box 200, 2998-3019, casefiles 2998-3019
  - Box 201, 3020-3051, casefiles 3020-3051
  - Box 202, 3051-3074, casefiles 3051-3074
  - Box 203, 3075-3111, casefiles 3075-3111
  - Box 204, 3112-3140, casefiles 3112-3140
  - Box 205, 3141-3175, casefiles 3141-3175
  - Box 206, 3175-3188, casefiles 3175-3188
  - Box 207, 3188-3199, casefiles 3188-3199
  - Box 208, 3200-3233, casefiles 3200-3233
  - Box 209, 3234-3259, casefiles 3234-3259
  - Box 210, 3260-3293, casefiles 3260-3293
  - Box 211, 3294-3337, casefiles 3294-3337
  - Box 212, 3338-3362, casefiles 3338-3362
  - Box 213, 3363-3389, casefiles 3363-3389
  - Box 214, 3390-3423, casefiles 3390-3423
  - Box 215, 3424-3459, casefiles 3424-3459
  - Box 216, 3460-3499, casefiles 3460-3499
  - Box 217, 3500-3530, casefiles 3500-3530
  - Box 218, 3530-3559, casefiles 3530-3559
  - Box 219, 3560-3597, casefiles 3560-3597
  - Box 220, 3597-3616, casefiles 3597-3616
  - Box 221, 3617-3652, casefiles 3617-3652
  - Box 222, 3653-3684, casefiles 3653-3684
  - Box 223, 3685-3729, casefiles 3685-3729
  - Box 224, 3730-3774, casefiles 3730-3774
  - Box 225, 3775-3799, casefiles 3775-3799
  - Box 226, 3800-3839, casefiles 3800-3839
  - Box 227, 3840-3899, casefiles 3840-3899
  - Box 228, 3900-3932, casefiles 3900-3932
  - Box 229, 3933-3976, casefiles 3933-3976
  - Box 230, 3977-4019, casefiles 3977-4019
  - Box 231, 4020-4052, casefiles 4020-4052
  - Box 232, 4053-4069, casefiles 4053-4069
  - Box 233, 4070-4099, casefiles 4070-4099
  - Box 234, 4100-4135, casefiles 4100-4135
  - Box 235, 4136-4173, casefiles 4136-4173
  - Box 236, 4174-4221, casefiles 4174-4221
  - Box 237, 4222-4279, casefiles 4222-4279
  - Box 238, 4280-4326, casefiles 4280-4326
  - Box 239, 4327-4381, casefiles 4327-4381
  - Box 240, 4382-4440, casefiles 4382-4440
  - Box 241, 4441-4505, casefiles 4441-4505
  - Box 242, 4506-4564, casefiles 4506-4564
  - Box 243, 4565-4619, casefiles 4565-4619
  - Box 244, 4620-4659, casefiles 4620-4659
  - Box 245, 4660-4705, casefiles 4660-4705
  - Box 246, 4706-4765, casefiles 4706-4765
  - Box 247, 4766-4835, casefiles 4766-4835
  - Box 248, 4836-4890, casefiles 4836-4890
  - Box 249, 4891-4950, casefiles 4891-4950
  - Box 250, 4951-4995, casefiles 4951-4995
  - Box 251, 4996-5014, casefiles 4996-5014
  - Box 252, 5014-5030, casefiles 5014-5030
  - Box 253, 5031-5054, casefiles 5031-5054
  - Box 254, 5055-5077, casefiles 5055-5077
  - Box 255, 5078-5107, casefiles 5078-5107
  - Box 256, 5108-5132, casefiles 5108-5132
  - Box 257, 5133-5153, casefiles 5133-5153
  - Box 258, 5154-5182, casefiles 5154-5182
  - Box 259, 5183-5207, casefiles 5183-5207
  - Box 260, 5208-5235, casefiles 5208-5235
  - Box 261, 5236-5260, casefiles 5236-5260
  - Box 262, 5261-5282, casefiles 5261-5282
  - Box 263, 5283-5307, casefiles 5283-5307
  - Box 264, 5308-5339, casefiles 5308-5339
  - Box 265, 5340-5376, casefiles 5340-5376
  - Box 266, 5377-5399, casefiles 5377-5399
  - Box 267, 5400-5429, casefiles 5400-5429
  - Box 268, 5430-5458, casefiles 5430-5458
  - Box 269, 5459-5492, casefiles 5459-5492
  - Box 270, 5493-5527, casefiles 5493-5527
  - Box 271, 5528-5556, casefiles 5528-5556
  - Box 272, 5557-5582, casefiles 5557-5582
  - Box 273, 5583-5610, casefiles 5583-5610
  - Box 274, 5611-5633, casefiles 5611-5633
  - Box 275, 5634-5658, casefiles 5634-5658
  - Box 276, 5659-5680, casefiles 5659-5680
  - Box 277, 5717-5745, casefiles 5717-5745
  - Box 278, 5681-5716, casefiles 5681-5716
  - Box 279, 5746-5788, casefiles 5746-5788
- Gladys Davis work files
  - Box 280
    - Work: E.C.F., Folder 280:1-280:2
    - Work: A.R.E. Health Service, Folder 280:3
    - Cures Book [Reports - Physical and Life], Folder 280:4
    - Research [General], Folder 280:5
    - Health Service: Physical Readings Brief [Physiology and Anatomy], Folder 280:6
  - Box 281
    - Health Service, Folder 281:1-281:3
    - Work: Ideals [Work Readings], Folder 281:4
    - Life Readings: Reports, Folder 281:5
  - Box 282
    - Mae Gimbert St. Clair materials, Folder 282:1
    - booklets [A Sequel to the Story of Edgar Cayce], 1948; Folder 282:2
    - Oath of Confidentiality [Edgar Cayce Foundation], Folder 282:3
    - binder [E.C.F. Charter History; A.R.E. Charter; A.R.E. By-Laws; Remington Rand Report], Folder 282:4
    - pamphlets [Cayce work], Folder 282:5
  - Box 283
    - pamphlets [A.R.E.], 1930-1980; Folder 283:1
    - Work: A.R.E., Folder 283:2-283:3
    - Work: E.C.F., Folder 283:4
    - Work: Old Brochures, etc.], Folder 283:5
  - Box 284
    - Work: A.R.E. Important Papers, Folder 284:1
    - Work: E.C.F. Important Papers, Folder 284:2
    - Work: E.C.F. staff, Folder 284:3-284:4
- Original readings and correspondence
  - Box 285
    - readings and related correspondence [2153 and family], Folder 285:1-285:24
    - readings [255], Folder 285:25
  - Box 286
    - group lessons [donated by 276], Folder 286:1
    - readings [255], Folder 286:2
    - readings [488], Folder 286:3
    - readings [282], Folder 286:4
    - readings [301], Folder 286:5
    - readings [276], Folder 286:6
    - readings [412], Folder 286:7
    - readings [378], Folder 286:8
    - readings [452], Folder 286:9
  - Box 287
    - readings [275], Folder 287:1
    - readings [Egyptian period], Folder 287:2
    - readings [Work], Folder 287:3
    - publications [A.R.E.] collected by 276, Folder 287:4
    - passenger record, Ellis Island [378; 255; 452; 282; 457], Folder 287:5
    - readings [53; 3795], Folder 287:6
    - readings [456; 5470], Folder 287:7
    - readings [5563], Folder 287:8
    - readings [101], Folder 287:9
    - readings [4983], Folder 287:10
- Reports addition
  - Box 288
    - readings reports, -282 to Gladys Davis Turner, 1975 -1123, 1950 -295's sister and husband to GDT, 1976 -275 to Gladys Davis Turner, 1976 -1208's wife to GDT, 1977 -1635's sister to GDT, 1977 -270, 1975 -1070 obituary, 1976 -1158 to GDT, 1976 -294, deposition of Minnie L. Dietrich in Cayce v. Noe, et. al., 1912 -294, Edgar Cayce to Mrs. Wolfe, 1941 -404 to GDT, 1977 -2991, 1944 -5676 to Edgar Cayce, 1906-1908 -2455 to GDT, 1975 -2329 to HLC, 1944 -409 to Edgar Cayce, 1931 -1212 to Edgar Cayce, 1931 -5014 to GDT, 1969 -1411 obituary, 1967 -1624 to GDT, 1969 -2682 to GDT, 1969 -979 to Edgar Cayce, 1933 -report on bruises from use of camphor-soda by Mrs. J.W. Cordak, 1956 -2297, 1969 -980 to Gladys, 1968 -750, 1969 -967, 1968 -3280, 1969 -1411, 1969 -5259 to Hugh Lynn Cayce, 1967 -2178, 1969 -1885, 1968 -4633, 1967 -1820, 1969 -404, 1953 -5267 obituary, 1969 -1872, 1969 -1597, 1969 -3152, 1969 -2073, 1968 -243 to Dr. Harold Reilly, 1968 -341, 1965 -4566 to HLC, 1968 -1703, 1968 -3106 to GDT, 1968 -5037 to Albert Turner, 1968 -2678 to GDT, 1967 -53 to HLC, 1967 -53 to HLC, 1968 -790, 1967 -3656 to GDT, 1968 -5104 to GDT, 1968 -953 to GDT, 1952 -3904 to GDT, 1968 -4496 to Robert Adriance, 1968 -5014's mother to GDT, 1968 -1089, 1968 -416, 1968 -1124, 1968 -3237, 1968 -4928, 1951 -3607, 1950 -1861, 1959 -902, 1950 -313, 1951
  - Box 289
  - Box 290
- Source file, Collection of secondary sources related to individual readings created by Gladys Davis Turner, Charles Sinex and the E.C.F. staff in the mid-1970s.
  - Box 291
    - 15-3; 39-3; 83-3; 120-1; 195-32, Folder 291:1
    - 239-1, Folder 291:2
    - 254; master indexes, Folder 291:3
    - 254-1 -- 254-49, Folder 291:4
    - 254-12 -- 254-19, Folder 291:5
    - 254-55 -- 254-70, Folder 291:6
    - 254-74 -- 254-109, Folder 291:7
    - 254-20 -- 254-29, Folder 291:8
    - 254-30 -- 254-39, Folder 291:9
    - 254-40 -- 254-48, Folder 291:10
    - 254-50 -- 254-55, Folder 291:11
    - 254-56 -- 254-59, Folder 291:12
    - 254-60 -- 254-69, Folder 291:13
    - 254-70 -- 254-89, Folder 291:14
    - 254-90 -- 254-99, Folder 291:15
    - 254-100 -- 254-109, Folder 291:16
    - 254-110 -- 254-116, Folder 291:17
    - 255-5, Folder 291:18
    - 262, Folder 291:19
    - 262-1 -- 262-18, Folder 291:20
    - 262-33 -- 262-61, Folder 291:21
  - Box 292
    - 262-100, Folder 292:1-292:3
    - 262-129 -- 262-130, Folder 292:4
    - 281, Folder 292:5
    - 281-1 -- 281-65, Folder 292:6
    - 281-48; 281-53; 281-59; 281-63; 281-64; 281-65; 282-6, Folder 292:7
    - 283-2; 288-1; 288-6; 288-8; 288-31; 288-50; 288-55, Folder 292:8
    - 294, Folder 292:9-292:10
    - 295-299, Folder 292:11-292:12
    - 404-440, Folder 292:13
    - 440-499, Folder 292:14
  - Box 293
    - 507-1 -- 588-1, Folder 293:1
    - 674-1 -- 877-26, Folder 293:2
    - 900-2 -- 900-464, Folder 293:3
    - 902-1 -- 996-12, Folder 293:4
    - 1005-2 -- 1292-1, Folder 293:5
    - 1332-1 -- 1497-6, Folder 293:6
    - 1521-1 -- 1683-1, Folder 293:7
    - 1700-1 -- 1747-3, Folder 293:8
    - 1755-1 -- 1796-1, Folder 293:9
    - 1800-3 -- 1800-19, Folder 293:10
    - 1800-21 -- 1800-34, Folder 293:11
    - 1815-1 -- 1990-3, Folder 293:12
    - 2004-1 -- 2087-7, Folder 293:13
  - Box 294
    - 2111-1 -- 2189-4, Folder 294:1
    - 2213-1 -- 2498-1, Folder 294:2
    - 2501-1 -- 2504-15, Folder 294:3
    - 2519-1 -- 2597-8, Folder 294:4
    - 2613-1 -- 2794-2, Folder 294:5
    - 2805-1 -- 2922-1, Folder 294:6
    - 3003-1 -- 3189-1, Folder 294:7
    - 3202-1 -- 3806-1, Folder 294:8
    - 3744, Folder 294:9
    - 3744 [Akashic records], Folder 294:10
    - 3744 [Astrology], Folder 294:11-294:12
    - 3744 [Eileen Garrett], Folder 294:13
    - 3744 [Environment and Heredity], Folder 294:14
    - 3744 [Mind the Builder], Folder 294:15
    - 3744 [Christian Mysticism], Folder 294:16
    - 3744 [Pendulums], Folder 294:17
    - 3744 [Planetary Sojourns], Folder 294:18
    - 3744 [Psychic Sources], Folder 294:19
    - 3744 [The Skull], Folder 294:20
  - Box 295
    - 3744 [Psychic Sources], Folder 295:1-295:5
    - Past Life Historical Documentation Project, Folder 295:6
    - 3812 -- 3976-10, Folder 295:7
    - 3976-15 -- 3982-1, Folder 295:8
    - 4003-1 -- 4531-3, Folder 295:9
    - 4905-1 -- 4905-29, Folder 295:11
    - 4905-30 -- 4905-54, Folder 295:12
    - 4905-56 -- 4908-1, Folder 295:13
    - 5204-1 -- 5728-1, Folder 295:14
  - Box 296
    - 5741-1 -- 5749-15, Folder 296:1-296:2
    - 5750-1 -- 5756-4, Folder 296:3
    - 294 [health conditions], Folder 296:4
    - 294 [hypnosis], Folder 296:5
    - 294 [physiology and anatomy], Folder 296:6
    - 294 [symbology], Folder 296:7
    - biographical information [Robert Adriance], Folder 296:8; also contains oral history material
    - biographical information [Eula Allen], Folder 296:9
    - biographical information [Billie Babcoke], Folder 296:10
    - biographical information [Samuel Benesch], Folder 296:11
    - biographical information [Edwin and Morton Blumenthal], Folder 296:12
    - biographical information [Marjorie Bonney], Folder 296:13
    - biographical information [Ruth Hagy Brod], Folder 296:14
    - biographical information [Mary Ellen Carter], Folder 296:15
    - biographical information [Hugh Lynn Cayce], Folder 296:16-296:17
    - biographical information [Gina Cerminara], Folder 296:18
    - biographical information [Nell Clairmonte], Folder 296:19
    - biographical information [Robert and Ann Clapp], Folder 296:20
    - biographical information [Russell Dyke], Folder 296:21
    - biographical information [Johan and Eloise Franco], Folder 296:22
    - biographical information [William Gaston], Folder 296:23
    - biographical information [Lydia Schrader Gray], Folder 296:24
    - biographical information [Manly Hall], Folder 296:25
    - biographical information [Ed Johnson], Folder 296:26
    - biographical information [Steve Jordan], Folder 296:27
    - biographical information [Wesley Ketchum], Folder 296:28
    - biographical information [Mary LaCroix], Folder 296:29
    - biographical information [Shane Miller], Folder 296:30
  - Box 297
    - biographical information [Anthony Mocciolo], Folder 297:1
    - biographical information [Anne Neumark], Folder 297:2
    - biographical information [Arch Ogden], Folder 297:3
    - biographical information [Freyda Pinkava], Folder 297:4
    - biographical information [Laurie Pratt], Folder 297:5
    - biographical information [Vic Reiffer], Folder 297:6
    - biographical information [Douglas Richards], Folder 297:7
    - biographical information [Birley Schoen], Folder 297:8
    - biographical information [Charlotte Schoen], Folder 297:9
    - biographical information [Lila Selover], Folder 297:10
    - biographical information [Jess Stearn], Folder 297:11
    - biographical information [Mark Thurston], Folder 297:12
    - biographical information [O.M. Wakefield], Folder 297:13